Matt Finucane / CV 1 of 4

Dublin, Ireland.

me@mattfinucane.com // https://mattfinucane.com

# **Profile**

I have fifteen years of experience working with a wide variety of projects across multiple domains and in different workplace settings, working on-site and remotely.

I focus on building web and mobile applications that are performant, scalable, and easy to maintain. I adhere to industry standards of the highest quality and work with Open-source software.

# **Skills**

- Development of mobile applications, both cross platform and native.
- Effective communication skills; training, presentations, documentation and delegation.
- Practice and advocate the highest development standards.
- In-depth understanding of technologies across multiple domains.
- · Strong analytical thinking and problem solving skills.
- Life-long learner with strong interest in continuous professional development.

# **Current tech stack**

| TypeScript        | JavaScript (ES)       | ReactJS              | Redux              |
|-------------------|-----------------------|----------------------|--------------------|
| Styled Components | SCSS/SASS/LESS        | Progressive Web Apps | CSS Grid           |
| NodeJS            | ExpressJS             | Docker / Compose     | MongoDB / Mongoose |
| Nginx             | Linux                 | Yarn / NPM           | webpack            |
| Jest              | React Testing Library | Supertest            | VSCode             |
| CircleCI          | Git                   | ESLint               | Stylelint          |
| Ligthouse         | BabelJS               | Function components  | React Hooks        |

# Legacy tech stack

| PHP                  | Python       | C/C++       | Objective C |
|----------------------|--------------|-------------|-------------|
| C#                   | PolymerJS    | MeteorJS    | jQuery      |
| Sencha Touch / ExtJS | Gulp / Grunt | Codelgniter | Perch CMS   |
| Wordpress            | Django       | MySQL       | Apache      |
| Hugo                 | Mocha / Chai | SinonJS     | WebStorm    |

Matt Finucane / CV 2 of 4

# **Experience**

## Travelport Digital as senior front-end engineer // Dublin

# January 2020 - Present

- Migrated client project from AngularJS to ReactJS with TypeScript.
- Replaced LESS/SASS with styled components (CSS in JS).
- Planned and implemented strategy to recover test coverage.
- Provided consultation to implement third party features seamlessly in client application.

# Mobility Trader GmbH as senior front-end engineer // Berlin

# January 2018 - December 2019

- Created and maintained a marketplace and CRM for the hey.car high quality used car platform.
- Managed technical debt for projects and maintained 100% test coverage.
- Platforms created using ReactJS with Redux for state management and Jest for testing.
- Mentored junior engineers, reviewed CVs and interviewed candidates.

## Freelance software engineer // Berlin

## December 2014 - January 2018

- Created a portfolio website using the Meteor JS website, making it reactive, localised and responsive.
- Released two Meteor JS based packages for the open source community.
- Working on two native iOS7/8 apps, both of which connect to third party REST services to aggregate data and manage user authentication.

# Things I Like GmbH as senior full-stack engineer // Berlin

#### June 2014 - December 2014

- Implemented a new website for the Monoqi B2B platform to facilitate communication and sales between designers and resellers.
- Improved purchase flows and address verification for the Monoqi B2C platform.
- Created new tools to improve front end development workflow for the team.
- Authored email templates for both platforms to increase conversion rates.

# Axel Springer Ideas as senior front-end engineer // Berlin

# October 2013 - May 2014

- Created a web application using the Meteor Javascript framework for an Axel Springer Ideas funded startup TunedIn to deliver native-like performance.
- Main features include a TV Guide and participation stream, both of which update in real time.
- Wrote unit and acceptance tests to ensure the product was stable and robust throughout each sprint.
- Supported the product owner and marketing team in creating the company website and marketing emails.

Matt Finucane / CV 3 of 4

# **Experience (continued)**

## iQContent Ltd as senior full-stack engineer (contract) // Dublin

## March 2013 - September 2013

 Created a knowledge based information portal (secure document sharing, retrieval and storage) for a large telecoms organisation in PHP.

- Optimised registration flow and integrated this with other CRM tools (Salesforce, Eloqua).
- Integrated the SCSS framework and optimised HTML templates to improve SEO performance.
- Developed HTML templates for the internal corporate IT intranet and assisted in integrating them to Microsoft Sharepoint.

#### Maithú IT Solutions as technical lead // Dublin

# **January 2012 – March 2013**

- Drove the development of multiple mobile applications.
- Developed TV guide software in HTML5 for set top boxes, smart TVs and web.
- Overhauled the Irish Times News app (iOS, Android) and integrated to their existing web infrastructure.
- Responsible for reviewing CVs, creating recruitment exercises and interviewing candidates for development roles.

# Paddy Power PLC as senior full-stack engineer // Dublin

# March 2010 - January 2012

- Our scrum approach to development ensured timely delivery of product phases and stakeholders were kept up to date with development on large projects.
- Maintained high performance websites under heavy server load.
- Upgraded the in-house CMS for Paddy Power Games and Casino to enable targeted content delivery for different user groups.
- Built a staff rostering and payroll processing system used by shop managers for all Paddy Power retail outlets.

# ClearWeb as senior full-stack engineer (freelance) // Dublin

# July 2008 - March 2010

- Created several bespoke content managed websites for clients using hand-coded html and php.
- · Leveraged Twitter and Facebook APIs, to optimise the clients' online offering.
- Provided web content strategy guidance to clients.
- Practiced excellent standards in web development to ensure organic SEO performance and accessibility.
- Initiated, managed and maintained long-lasting professional client relationships.

Matt Finucane / CV 4 of 4

# **Experience (continued)**

# Net a Porter as full-stack engineer // London

## **July 2007 – July 2008**

- Redeveloped the HTML and CSS during a complete overhaul of the company website.
- Created an internal WYSIWYG tool to author promotional emails and newsletter templates.
- Designed and built the in house intranet portal, tying it into existing LDAP servers. This enabled seamless integration with existing user logins.
- Provided ongoing maintenance to website product pages to optimise the eCommerce purchase flows.

## FindMyPast.com as full-stack engineer // London

# September 2006 - June 2007

- Upgraded site standards compliancy in XHTML and CSS.
- · Coordinated internal knowledge sharing through regular web standards training.
- · Created HTML email templates for marketing campaigns.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and enhancements for the company website.

# AOL Technologies Ltd as associate software engineer // Dublin

## July 2005 - June 2006

- Created a web app to monitor RSS feeds from news providers.
- Built an XSLT processor to populate XML feeds to databases.
- Upgraded servers and software from HPUX to Linux and authored the associated technical documentation.

# Qualifications

# BSc. in Computer Applications (Honours) // Dublin City University September 2001 - June 2005

- Modules include Java software development, Business process management, Computer Graphics, Database administration and the Software development life-cycle (waterfall).
- Alcatel CIT, France: created a logging system for GSM cell towers (INTRA work placement).
- Developed a mobile 2D game using J2ME (Final year project).

## **Interests**

- Passionate about technology inside and outside of my professional life.
- Self-taught in iOS and Android development. Projects can be found on GitHub.
- Successfully participated in the '24 The Web' design challenge as lead developer.
- Regularly provide pro-bono web development to charities and startups.
- Photography, reading, running and cycling.